<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Coditva&#39;s Old Blog</title>
    <link>https://coditva.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Coditva&#39;s Old Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 18:04:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coditva.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New found love - i3wm</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/new-found-love-i3wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 18:04:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/new-found-love-i3wm/</guid>
      <description>So I had enough of Gnome breaking every now and then, filling up my RAM with all sorts of unwanted services and decided to switch to something new. I wanted something that would reduce the whole dependency cycle; something which does not make you choose between eye-candy and performance.
And i3wm caught my eye, which claims to be &amp;ldquo;targeted at advanced users and developers.&amp;rdquo; I looked around for some screenshots for how does it look and was surprised to find that every one of them was drastically different from the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a monArchy!</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/its-a-monarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 03:15:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/its-a-monarchy/</guid>
      <description>Why is this Arch Linux such a big deal among people? It can&amp;rsquo;t be that tough! I&amp;rsquo;ll just install it and see for myself.
So, here I am, installing a new Linux flavor just for the heck of it. But I won&amp;rsquo;t replace my current OS just yet. Let me install it in a virtual box. After an easy download from their website, I have my hands on the iso image and I fire up my virtual box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elementary, my dear Watson</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/elementary-my-dear-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 10:35:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/elementary-my-dear-watson/</guid>
      <description>The new OS is in! Welcome, drumrolls Elementary OS 0.4 Loki. It was a hard decision really, leaving all the customizability of Ubuntu and switching to the somewhat constricted Loki. But the best part about it is that Loki doesn&amp;rsquo;t require that amount of customization. The UI looks, and feels, like a Mac but there are a few differences here and there. Actually, there are many. Nonetheless, being built from Ubuntu, the transition wasn&amp;rsquo;t much a difference, except for the escape from the Unity look that bored me to death.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>