<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gsoc on Coditva&#39;s Old Blog</title>
    <link>https://coditva.github.io/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gsoc on Coditva&#39;s Old Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 07:33:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coditva.github.io/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress at the end of GSoC with Neovim</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/progress-at-the-end-of-gsoc-with-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 07:33:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/progress-at-the-end-of-gsoc-with-neovim/</guid>
      <description>As we come to the end of three months of the coding extravaganza as a part of GSoC, I would like to share the progress we made so far and what is left to do as a part of Improving the UI protocol in Neovim with Björn Linse as my mentor.
What is in place  Grid based updatesThis post describes the grid-based updates in Neovim. The work for this is almost complete with tests and documentation in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Window Grid Updates in Neovim</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/window-grid-updates-in-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 22:43:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/window-grid-updates-in-neovim/</guid>
      <description>This post is in continuation with this post.
Neovim has come to be a very hackable, developer friendly version of Vim. It actually is what their website claims to be: literally the future of vim and Vim-fork focused on extensibility and usability. One of the goals of nvim is to allow UIs to set different grid-sizes for each window and receive grid-based events.
Why do we need grid-based updates and different grid-sizes than what nvim sets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress After Two Weeks Into GSoC with Neovim</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/progress-after-two-weeks-into-gsoc-with-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 01:07:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/progress-after-two-weeks-into-gsoc-with-neovim/</guid>
      <description>This post is in continuation with this post.
Two weeks have passed since the coding period began for Google Summer of Code on 14th May. After setting up my system in a room with a loud music system, I officially began coding.
The progress so far The first task that I needed to do was to break up the one global grid used for screen-handling into smaller per-window grids which would later let external UIs manage them individually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code with Neovim</title>
      <link>https://coditva.github.io/blog/google-summer-of-code-with-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 11:03:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coditva.github.io/blog/google-summer-of-code-with-neovim/</guid>
      <description>So, I got selected as a student applicant for the Google Summer of Code (or GSoC) and will be working with Neovim over the course of next three months!
Neovim is a fork of Vim, one of the most loved text editors that is used not only by the coding community but people from all over walks of life. I have been a devoted worshipper of Vim for about two years now and have fought in the Editor wars whenever the need arose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>